In this video, I'd like to
在这段视频中 我想要
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
convey to you, the main intuitions
传达给你一个直观的感受
behind how regularization works.
告诉你正规化是如何进行的
And, we'll also write down
而且 我们还要写出
the cost function that we'll use, when we were using regularization.
我们使用正规化时 需要使用的代价函数
With the hand drawn examples that
根据我们幻灯片上的
we have on these slides, I
这些例子
think I'll be able to convey part of the intuition.
我想我可以给你一个直观的感受
But, an even better
但是 一个更好的
way to see for yourself, how
让你自己去理解正规化
regularization works, is if
如何工作的方法是
you implement it, and, see it work for yourself.
你自己亲自去实现它 并且看看它是如何工作的
And, if you do the
如果在这节课后
appropriate exercises after this,
你进行一些适当的练习
you get the chance
你就有机会亲自体验一下
to self see regularization in action for yourself.
正规化到底是怎么工作的
So, here is the intuition.
那么 这里就是一些直观解释
In the previous video, we saw
在前面的视频中 我们看到了
that, if we were to fit
如果说我们要
a quadratic function to this
用一个二次函数来
data, it gives us a pretty good fit to the data.
拟合这些数据 它给了我们一个对数据很好的拟合
Whereas, if we were to
然而 如果我们
fit an overly high order
用一个更高次的
degree polynomial, we end
多项式去拟合 我们最终
up with a curve that may fit
可能得到一个曲线
the training set very well, but,
能非常好地拟合训练集 但是
really not be a,
这真的不是一个好的结果
but overfit the data
它过度拟合了数据
poorly, and, not generalize well.
因此 一般性并不是很好
Consider the following, suppose we
让我们考虑下面的假设
were to penalize, and, make
我们想要加上惩罚项 从而使
the parameters theta 3 and theta 4 really small.
参数 θ3 和 θ4 足够的小
Here's what I
这里我的意思就是
mean, here is our optimization
这是我们的优化目标
objective, or here is our
或者客观的说 这就是我们需要
optimization problem, where we minimize
优化的问题 我们需要尽量减少
our usual squared error cause function.
代价函数的均方误差
Let's say I take this objective
对于这个函数
and modify it and add
我们对它进行一些 添加一些项
to it, plus 1000 theta
加上 1000 乘以 θ3 的平方
3 squared, plus 1000 theta 4 squared.
再加上 1000 乘以 θ4 的平方
1000 I am just writing down as some huge number.
1000 只是我随便写的某个较大的数字而已
Now, if we were to
现在 如果我们要
minimize this function, the
最小化这个函数
only way to make this
为了使这个
new cost function small is
新的代价函数最小化
if theta 3 and data
我们要让 θ3 和 θ4
4 are small, right?
尽可能小 对吧？
Because otherwise, if you have
因为 如果你有
a thousand times theta 3, this
1000 乘以 θ3 这个
new cost functions gonna be big.
新的代价函数将会是很大的
So when we minimize this
所以 当我们最小化
new function we are going
这个新的函数时 我们将使
to end up with theta 3
θ3 的值
close to 0 and theta
接近于0
4 close to 0, and as
θ4 的值也接近于0
if we're getting rid
就像我们忽略了
of these two terms over there.
这两个值一样
And if we do that, well then,
如果我们做到这一点
if theta 3 and theta 4
如果 θ3 和 θ4
close to 0 then we are
接近0 那么我们
being left with a quadratic function,
将得到一个近似的二次函数
and, so, we end up with
所以 我们最终
a fit to the data, that's, you know, quadratic
恰当地拟合了数据  你知道
function plus maybe, tiny
二次函数加上一些项
contributions from small terms,
这些很小的项 贡献很小
theta 3, theta 4, that they may be very close to 0.
因为 θ3 θ4 它们是非常接近于0的
And, so, we end up with
所以 我们最终得到了
essentially, a quadratic function, which is good.
实际上 很好的一个二次函数
Because this is a
因为这是一个
much better hypothesis.
更好的假设
In this particular example, we looked at the effect
在这个具体的例子中 我们看到了
of penalizing two of
惩罚这两个
the parameter values being large.
大的参数值的效果
More generally, here is the idea behind regularization.
更一般地 这里给出了正规化背后的思路
The idea is that, if we
这种思路就是 如果我们
have small values for the
的参数值
parameters, then, having
对应一个较小值的话
small values for the parameters,
就是说 参数值比较小
will somehow, will usually correspond
那么往往我们会得到一个
to having a simpler hypothesis.
形式更简单的假设
So, for our last example, we
所以 我们最后一个例子中
penalize just theta 3 and
我们惩罚的只是 θ3 和
theta 4 and when both
θ4 使这两个
of these were close to zero,
值均接近于零
we wound up with a much simpler
我们得到了一个更简单的假设
hypothesis that was essentially a quadratic function.
也即这个假设大抵上是一个二次函数
But more broadly, if we penalize all
但更一般地说 如果我们就像这样
the parameters usually that, we
惩罚的其它参数 通常我们
can think of that, as trying
可以把它们都想成是
to give us a simpler hypothesis
得到一个更简单的假设
as well because when, you
因为你知道
know, these parameters are
当这些参数越接近这个例子时
as close as you in this
假设的结果越接近
example, that gave us a quadratic function.
一个二次函数
But more generally, it is
但更一般地
possible to show that having
可以表明
smaller values of the parameters
这些参数的值越小
corresponds to usually smoother
通常对应于越光滑的函数
functions as well for the simpler.
也就是更加简单的函数
And which are therefore, also, less prone to overfitting.
因此 就不易发生过拟合的问题
I realize that the reasoning for
我知道
why having all the parameters be small.
为什么要所有的部分参数变小的这些原因
Why that corresponds to a simpler
为什么越小的参数对应于一个简单的假设
hypothesis; I realize that
我知道这些原因
reasoning may not be entirely clear to you right now.
对你来说现在不一定完全理解
And it is kind of hard
但现在解释起来确实比较困难
to explain unless you implement
除非你自己实现一下
yourself and see it for yourself.
自己亲自运行了这部分
But I hope that the example of
但是我希望 这个例子中
having theta 3 and theta
使 θ3 和 θ4
4 be small and how
很小 并且这样做
that gave us a simpler
能给我们一个更加简单的
hypothesis, I hope that
假设 我希望这个例子
helps explain why, at least give
有助于解释原因 至少给了
some intuition as to why this might be true.
我们一些直观感受 为什么这应该是这样的
Lets look at the specific example.
来让我们看看具体的例子
For housing price prediction we
对于房屋价格预测我们
may have our hundred features
可能有上百种特征
that we talked about where may
我们谈到了一些可能的特征
be x1 is the size, x2
比如说 x1 是房屋的尺寸
is the number of bedrooms, x3
x2 是卧室的数目
is the number of floors and so on.
x3 是房屋的层数等等
And we may we may have a hundred features.
那么我们可能就有一百个特征
And unlike the polynomial
跟前面的多项式例子不同
example, we don't know, right,
我们是不知道的 对吧
we don't know that theta 3,
我们不知道 θ3
theta 4, are the high order polynomial terms.
θ4 是高阶多项式的项
So, if we have just a
所以 如果我们有一个袋子
bag, if we have just a
如果我们有一百个特征
set of a hundred features, it's hard
在这个袋子里 我们是很难
to pick in advance which are
提前选出那些
the ones that are less likely to be relevant.
关联度更小的特征的
So we have a hundred or a hundred one parameters.
也就是说如果我们有一百或一百零一个参数
And we don't know which
我们不知道
ones to pick, we
挑选哪一个
don't know which
我们并不知道
parameters to try to pick, to try to shrink.
如何选择参数 如何缩小参数的数目
So, in regularization, what we're
因此在正规化里
going to do, is take our
我们要做的事情 就是把我们的
cost function, here's my cost function for linear regression.
代价函数 这里就是线性回归的代价函数
And what I'm going to do
我现在要做的就是
is, modify this cost
来修改这个代价函数
function to shrink all
从而缩小
of my parameters, because, you know,
我所有的参数值 因为你知道
I don't know which
我不知道是哪个
one or two to try to shrink.
哪一个或两个要去缩小
So I am going to modify my
所以我就修改我的
cost function to add a term at the end.
代价函数 在这后面添加一项
Like so we have square brackets here as well.
就像我们在方括号里的这项
When I add an extra
当我添加一个额外的
regularization term at the
正则化项的时候
end to shrink every
我们收缩了每个
single parameter and so this
参数 并且因此
term we tend to shrink
我们会使
all of my parameters theta 1,
我们所有的参数 θ1
theta 2, theta 3 up
θ2 θ3
to theta 100.
直到 θ100 的值变小
By the way, by convention the summation
顺便说一下 按照惯例来讲
here starts from one so I
我们从第一个这里开始
am not actually going penalize theta
所以我实际上没有去惩罚 θ0
zero being large.
因此 θ0 的值是大的
That sort of the convention that,
这就是一个约定
the sum I equals one through
从1到 n 的求和
N, rather than I equals zero
而不是从0到 n 的求和
through N. But in practice,
但其实在实践中
it makes very little difference, and,
这只会有非常小的差异
whether you include, you know,
无论你是否包括这项
theta zero or not, in
就是 θ0 这项
practice, make very little difference to the results.
实际上 结果只有非常小的差异
But by convention, usually, we regularize
但是按照惯例 通常情况下我们还是只
only theta  through theta
从 θ1 到 θ100 进行正规化
100. Writing down
这里我们写下来
our regularized optimization objective,
我们的正规化优化目标
our regularized cost function again.
我们的正规化后的代价函数
Here it is. Here's J of
就是这样的
theta where, this term
J(θ) 这个项
on the right is a regularization
右边的这项就是一个正则化项
term and lambda
并且 λ
here is called the regularization parameter and
在这里我们称做正规化参数
what lambda does, is it
λ 要做的就是控制
controls a trade off
在两个不同的目标中
between two different goals.
的一个平衡关系
The first goal, capture it
第一个目标
by the first goal objective, is
第一个需要抓住的目标
that we would like to train,
就是我们想要训练
is that we would like to fit the training data well.
使假设更好地拟合训练数据
We would like to fit the training set well.
我们希望假设能够很好的适应训练集
And the second goal is,
而第二个目标是
we want to keep the parameters
我们想要保持参数值较小
small, and that's captured by
这就是第二项的目标
the second term, by the regularization objective. And by the regularization term.
通过正则化目标函数
And what lambda, the regularization
这就是λ 这个正则化
parameter does is the controls the trade of
参数需要控制的
between these two
它会这两者之间的平衡
goals, between the goal of fitting the training set well
目标就是平衡拟合训练的目的
and the
和
goal of keeping the parameter plan
保持参数值较小的目的
small and therefore keeping the hypothesis relatively
从而来保持假设的形式相对简单
simple to avoid overfitting.
来避免过度的拟合
For our housing price prediction
对于我们的房屋价格预测来说
example, whereas, previously, if
这个例子 尽管我们之前有
we had fit a very high
我们已经用非常高的
order polynomial, we may
高阶多项式来拟合 我们将会
have wound up with a very,
得到一个
sort of wiggly or curvy function like
非常弯曲和复杂的曲线函数
this. If you still fit a high order polynomial
就像这个 如果你还是用高阶多项式拟合
with all the polynomial
就是用这里所有的多项式特征来拟合的话
features in there, but instead,
但现在我们不这样了
you just make sure, to use
你只需要确保使用了
this sole of regularized objective, then what
正规化目标的方法
you can get out is in
那么你就可以得到
fact a curve that isn't
实际上是一个曲线 但这个曲线不是
quite a quadratic function, but is
一个真正的二次函数
much smoother and much simpler
而是更加的流畅和简单
and maybe a curve like the magenta
也许就像这条紫红色的曲线一样
line that, you know, gives a
那么 你知道的
much better hypothesis for this data.
这样就得到了对于这个数据更好的假设
Once again, I realize
再一次说明下
it can be a bit difficult to see why strengthening the
我了解这部分有点难以明白 为什么加上
parameters can have
参数的影响可以具有
this effect, but if you
这种效果 但如果你
implement yourselves with regularization
亲自实现了正规化
you will be able to see
你将能够看到
this effect firsthand.
这种影响的最直观的感受
In regularized linear regression, if
在正规化线性回归中 如果
the regularization parameter monitor
正规化参数值
is set to be very large,
被设定为非常大
then what will happen is
那么将会发生什么呢？
we will end up penalizing the
我们将会非常大地惩罚
parameters theta 1, theta
参数θ1 θ2
2, theta 3, theta
θ3 θ4
4 very highly.
也就是说
That is, if our hypothesis is this is one down at the bottom.
如果我们的假设是底下的这个
And if we end up penalizing
如果我们最终惩罚
theta 1, theta 2, theta
θ1 θ2 θ3
3, theta 4 very heavily, then we
θ4 在一个非常大的程度 那么我们
end up with all of these parameters close to zero, right?
会使所有这些参数接近于零的 对不对？
Theta 1 will be close to zero; theta 2 will be close to zero.
θ1 将接近零   θ2 将接近零
Theta three and theta four
θ3 和 θ4
will end up being close to zero.
最终也会接近于零
And if we do that, it's as
如果我们这么做 那么就是
if we're getting rid of these
我们的假设中
terms in the hypothesis so that
相当于去掉了这些项 并且使
we're just left with a hypothesis
我们只是留下了一个简单的假设
that will say that.
这个假设只能表明
It says that, well, housing
那就是 房屋价格
prices are equal to theta zero,
就等于 θ0 的值
and that is akin to fitting
那就是类似于拟合了
a flat horizontal straight line to the data.
一条水平直线 对于数据来说
And this is an
这就是一个
example of underfitting, and
欠拟合 (underfitting)
in particular this hypothesis, this
这种情况下这一假设
straight line it just fails
它是条失败的直线
to fit the training set
对于训练集来说
well. It's just a fat straight
这只是一条平滑直线
line, it doesn't go, you know, go near.
它没有任何趋势
It doesn't go anywhere near most of the training examples.
它不会去趋向大部分训练样本的任何值
And another way of saying this
这句话的另??一种方式来表达就是
is that this hypothesis has
这种假设有
too strong a preconception or
过于强烈的"偏见" 或者
too high bias that housing
过高的偏差 (bais)
prices are just equal
认为预测的价格只是
to theta zero, and despite
等于 θ0 并且
the clear data to the contrary,
尽管我们的数据集
you know chooses to fit a sort
选择去拟合一条
of, flat line, just a
扁平的直线 仅仅是一条
flat horizontal line. I didn't draw that very well.
扁平的水平线  我画得不好
This just a horizontal flat line
对于数据来说
to the data. So for
这只是一条水平线 因此
regularization to work well, some
为了使正则化运作良好
care should be taken,
我们应当注意一些方面
to choose a good choice for
应该去选择一个不错的
the regularization parameter lambda as well.
正则化参数 λ
And when we talk about multi-selection
并且当我们以后讲到多重选择时
later in this course, we'll talk
在后面的课程中 我们将讨论
about a way, a variety
一种方法
of ways for automatically choosing
一系列的方法来自动选择
the regularization parameter lambda as well. So, that's
正则化参数 λ  所以
the idea of the high regularization
这就是高度正则化的思路
and the cost function reviews in
回顾一下代价函数
order to use regularization In the
为了使用正则化
next two videos, lets take
在接下来的两段视频中 让我们
these ideas and apply them
把这些概念 应用到
to linear regression and to
到线性回归和
logistic regression, so that
逻辑回归中去
we can then get them to
那么我们就可以让他们
avoid overfitting.
避免过度拟合了